# **Burak Kiran**

## Computer Scientist

I am a 24 year old Computer Scientist, who currently studies M.Sc. Information Systems Management at Technische Universität Berlin. Recently I have graduated from Technische Universität Berlin in B.Sc. Computer Science. I have been working at MyToys Group since December 2021 as a process automation engineer. I like improving myself in my freetime and believe a high number of the skills I gained are from my freetime projects. In the last 5 years I focused mostly on three topics and plan to continue my career with these topics: Full Stack Development, Data Science, Machine Learning. My personal webpage contains the github links and the descriptions for more projects in detail: https://kiran1226.github.io/devportfolio/

# **Work Experience**

MyToys Group, Berlin - Process Automation Engineer

12.2021 - now

- Job: Working Student
- Main task: Automation of internal "Product Management Excellence" team workflows
- Software Model: Scrum Model with 2 week sprints (Jira)
- Automating workflows by creating webapps and connecting to different API's with python (example: Jira)
- Filtering and cleaning data with python in excel and csv format
- Web Scraping to get information about products
- CHecking data correctness with SQL and Python
- Focussed Python Libraries: NumPy, Pandas, Requests,
   Tkinter, BeautifulSoup, Django, Flask, SQLAlchemy

#### GetHenry, Berlin - Data Collection and Reporting

11.2021 - 12.2021

- Job: Minijob
- Entering bicycle information to google sheets (Data Entry)
- Checking whether each bike has the correct information (Data Control)
- Gained skill: **Detail Orientation**

#### Nutricia GmbH, Erlangen - Company Overview Intern

08.2018 - 08.2018

- Visiting different departments and understanding the big picture
- Recording the complaints through SAP

#### Contact

https://kiran1226.github.io/devportfolio/

+49 176 204 05845 burakkiran1226@gmail.com Beuthstraβe 15, 10117 Berlin, Germany

## **Spoken Languages**

English (C1)

German (C2)

Turkish (C2)

### **Skills (Stars represent years)**

Algorithms and Data Structures: \* \* \*

Analysis and Linear Algebra:

API Usage: \*\*

Assembly: \*

Automation: \* \*

· \*

Data Analysis / Visualisation:

Flask \*\*

Git: \*\*\*

HTML: \* \* \*

Java: \* \* \*

JavaScript: \*\*\*

Jupiter: \*\*

Probability and statistics: \*

Python: \* \* \*

₹:

# **Projects**

# Visual Perception Bachelor Thesis (Individual Project)

10.2022 - 03.2023, Berlin

- Analyzing and Plotting different experiment data from literature
- Predicting a new experiment results through the analyzed data with the help of linear regression
- Used Python Libraries: Pandas, numpy, scipy, math, seaborn, matplotlib, os

#### **Smart City and Autonomous Cars (Group Project)**

10.2022 - 03.2023, Berlin

- Creating a secure traffic light system for autonomous cars
- Used Technologies: Java, Maven

### Data Science (Group Project)

04.2021 - 08.2021, Berlin

- Aiming to guess songs future trajectory in Billboard 100 by analyzing the past weeks Billboard 100 place
- Aiming to answer the question: How can a song stay the longest in Billboard 100?
- Used Technologies: matplotlib, seaborn, numpy, pandas, time
- Git (Scrum Masters Repo):
   https://git.tu-berlin.de/ravidhausmann/billboard-lo
   ngevity- prediction

# Scientific Programming with Python (Individual Project)

04.2020 - 08.2020, Berlin

- 6 Mini school projects
- Goal: Learn implementing Linear Algebra with python

SQL: \*\*

Scientific Research: \*\*

VS code: \*\*\*

#### Education

### Technische Universität Berlin, Berlin - M.Sc.

2022 - now, Berlin

Study Of Information Systems Management

### Technische Universität Berlin, Berlin - B.Sc.

2018 - 2023, Berlin

Study Of Computer Science

# Deutsche Schule, Istanbul - High School.

2013 - 2018, Istanbul

Study Of Computer Science

#### **Certificates:**

#### **IBM Data Science Course**

A 5 month Data Science Course to train candidates on a "Junior Data Scientist Level".
Here is the link for a better description:
https://www.coursera.org/professiona

l-certificates/ibm-data-science

#### **Hobbies:**

Table-Tennis

Beach Volleyball

F1

Traveling